Hello! In this video, I will show you the results
of me spending 100 hours reviewing the source code
of Elastic applications to score some bounties
in Elastic bug bounty program. Unfortunately,
my result is not great, and if you're only
interested in success stories, then this video
is not for you. But if you also want to see what I
did wrong, what I did well, and what I did learn,
then stay with me. Enjoy! So first two days were
pretty much spent on the whole setup. I wanted to
be able to debug Kibana to just have an edge over
other hunters. And setting up is never pleasurable
activity for me. But when doing the bug bounty,
every time I spent some time preparing myself,
I know that I will be ahead of those hunters who
didn't want to invest this time now and will have
worse environment for testing later. I wanted to
be able to debug both Kibana and Elasticsearch.
Because Kibana is an application to present data,
but the data is actually stored in Elasticsearch
database. And I chose Kibana as my main
target, but I also wanted to be able to
debug Elasticsearch. But it was quite hard
to to set up and at the end, I was able to
to debug Kibana but not Elasticsearch. I only
used Docker image for it. Then, I read some
reports from Hackerone to know what to expect,
what are the weak sides of Kibana and I started
testing. The way I would test the application is
I would simply start using it from the browser
and choose a functionality that I would like to
to test. And then I would start understanding
what happens. I would start reading the code,
putting in breakpoints to see what issues can be
in this place of code. And I really enjoyed this
faze. Every day, I was understanding more and more
functionalities. I saw how they worked. And to be
honest, Kibana seemed a little bit sketchy to me.
You know, sometimes when you test an
application or look at the source code,
you just feel it's secure. That the developers
saw everything you can try. In this case,
I felt it was written really badly. For example,
there are a lot of path traversals and you see
that someone wrote this application without this
security issue in mind, but those traversals are
fixed in places where user input could actually
reach those dangerous places. For example,
here is a code that takes... Kibana takes
the request from the user and forwards it
to Elasticsearch. This is quite common actually.
And there is path traversal in this functionality.
But this input has to be an ID of an object
that already exists so you can't use the
that ../ because there is no such object. But
there's another way that this function allows
which is using a wildcard. And without getting
into details of this logic, I was able
to prepare this payload which would both look to
Kibana like a wildcard, not throw an error, and,
most importantly, it would also give me the the
path traversal. The thing is that after writing
this, I was already happy. I thought that I will
submit my my first report. But it turned out
that this function by default has allowWildcards
argument set to false. And there is not a single
place in Kibana source code where this function
is called with allowWildcards argument. It's
there for a reason so it was used sometime in
the past, but apparently it is no not no longer
vulnerable. But it was. And that pretty much
sums up a lot of my time spent there. So I saw
a place which looked like it's vulnerable but
but it wasn't. Next, after finding out that
this particular spot is not vulnerable, I would
try to create a code signature, which is just
a proper search to find a similar vulnerability
in other place of the source code where maybe it
would be vulnerable. Here is another example which
I found by looking for similar code patterns.
This is a functionality which allows you
to browse some external packages on Kibana.
And those files are stored on another server - on
Elastic Package Registry and this is the way that
the path is created to make a request to EPR.
But you can see that there is no URL encoding,
so there is path traversal here. However, Elastic
package registry is public anyway, so there is no
impact to this. If you could find an open redirect
on a package registry, it would be an SSRF.
But I looked through the whole source code
of the package registry and I didn't find
the open redirect, but if you want you
can give it a try. And here is another
case where the code looks bad. There is
a vulnerability, but it is not exploitable,
so perhaps it's not the vulnerability after
all. And after a few cases like this, I started
questioning my choice to to stick to Kibana and
I wanted to look for other targets. And I
was very hopeful when I found out about Enterprise
Search application. Unlike most Elastic products,
it is not open source. But you can install it
from Docker image. And you know that if you can
install something using Docker Image, you can
extract at least some kind of bytecode. And I
wanted to extract this bytecode and maybe attack
this application, which is not as easy to get.
But turns out this is how the jar files look after
the the decompilation. Every single file looks
exactly the same but the only difference is
this string or these bytes. Turns out that this
technology is called JRuby. And the way it works
is you have some kind of Ruby bytecode although
bytecode isn't a valid word to describe this.
And it is executed by a Java program, and the
problem is there are no public JRuby decompilers
available in the Internet. The first result that
pops up when you Google this is a private repository from
GitLab, from the guy who, by no accident, is top
one hacker on Elastic bug bounty program. And I
say it's no accident because I talked with him
and he told me that Kibana is quite hardened at
the moment and he finds most of most of his bugs
on Enterprise Search due to the fact that he's
the only one that has the source code access to
that. I also thought about writing the compiler
myself, but I decided that maybe 100 hours is not
enough for that so I ended up not doing this. And
those situations showed me that my hacker instincts
are correct - I'm just too late to the party.
But even though I wasn't finding a lot of bugs,
you probably know that not finding bugs motivates
you more than finding the bugs, because then
you try to go deeper, you try to research new
attack techniques... And I was learning a lot
and I had quite a lot of materials to share in
BBRE newsletter in BBRE Premium. For example,
take this one from BBRE Premium #25.
You have these 3 regexes and think about
which of them which will match and which of
these inputs. Specifically, the question is which
regexes have escaped dots and which are wildcards.
The first one obviously matches wildcards, which
means that the dot is matched to any character.
I'm sure that you knew that already. The third one
matches escaped dots, which means the dot
only matches the dot, but the middle one,
I would think it would also match a literal
dot, but turns out it doesn't. And in this case,
the dot is the wildcard. I am not the only
one who doesn't know this because the Kibana
developers don't know this either. This
is the code where they have badly written
regexes. Unfortunately, to my knowledge, this is
not in a place which is a security vulnerability.
And after some time, I found a bug. I was
able to control the source of the image.
It doesn't allow you to to execute XSS, but it
allows you to point this this URL to a logout.
And then every single person that visits this
address, visits the website where your payload
is present, are logged out of the application. So
this is a functionality-level denial of service.
It can be a medium-risk bug if it's in a critical
functionality, maybe even high sometimes. In this
case it wasn't, but it was a bug. But the denial
of service bugs were out of scope of Elastic. And
I would probably ignore this this rule if I would
really find like one-click denial of service
bug for the whole application. But in this case,
I decided that it is not risky enough for me to
to ignore the policy. So I didn't report this, but
after a few weeks, I checked the policy again and
turned out that they made a change, effectively
removing denial of service from out of scope
vulnerabilities. So I started writing the
report. I confirmed that other users can also
see my payload and I started to write the report.
But unfortunately, turned out that I copied the
wrong session cookie when confirming this bug
and I was the only one who could see my payload
so I could only logout myself of the application.
So there is no impact to this so I ended up not
reporting this bug, which wasn't a high risk
anyway - it was definitely a low risk.
But I hoped that I will at least report
something finally, which was a bit discouraging.
So again, I started jumping between different
assets of Elastic. That included Elastic cloud.
And quickly, I found low risk vulnerability
there, but unfortunately it was a duplicate.
And this time I did submit the report, but it
was a duplicate and judging by the report ID,
it was a duplicate of a bug from a year before. So
they probably just don't care about it, which was
yet another discouraging moment. And after that,
I decided that I will stick with Kibana until the
end. And I think I spent these last hours really
well. At the beginning, I told you that I browsed
Hackerone for public bug bounty reports. But, of
course, there are not many bugs disclosed there.
But turns out that Elastic has its own bug
tracker and there are other vulnerabilities.
And, of course, there are no proof of concepts
there, but they are public. So I started to look
at a bugs from this tracker and to reverse patches
to these bugs to maybe find similar ones and
understand the application better. And I think it
was a really good thing. It taught me a lot. And
it gave me much better understanding of the bug
actually than just reading the hackerone report
because I had to understand the whole context, I
had to understand the source code around this bug.
And this gave me really good understanding.
For example, here's an interesting XSS which
doesn't exist in the default configuration
because it is in the code written by Kibana
but to use this code, you have to create your
own plugin. So there is a code in Kibana, you
have to create your own plugin and you have to use
one particular library, one particular function
that Kibana gives you so this bug is actually
present. So you don't misuse the library,
you use it properly and there is an XSS. So
what I started to do after this was I started
to create my own plugins. It was a little bit hard
for me, especially that I am not TypeScript
developer. I can read the code but I'm not that
good at writing and I think I started doing this
too late. I was able to create my plugins, but
it was not enough time to experiment with using
different libraries, different use cases.
But it was definitely, definitely worth it.
And then finally after 92 hours, out of 100, I
found the valid bug. I actually found it by accident.
I was looking for something else and I noticed
in the file next to the one I was inspecting,
there was a vulnerable code which I immediately
spotted and even though it was barely exploitable,
it was a valid bug. So I submitted it and they
didn't resolve it yet and didn't disclose it
so I can't tell you what it was. From the
technical standpoint, it's not very interesting
unfortunately. They paid me $584 for it. And
unfortunately, that is the final result of my
challenge. For those of you who don't know how
this works, 100 hours for me is, a month of
full time work. So obviously, I do other
things which includes these videos, so it was
spread across four months for me. But if I would
only do bug bounty, then this challenge would
take me one month. So that's how I compare these
results to one month's salary of a full time job.
Actually, I would expect such challenge to take me
about two months, but this one took me almost four
just because I procrastinated a lot, which was
simply caused by not finding bugs. So what are the
lessons that I learned from this challenge? The
first one is to not go for programs about which
you hear from someone else because they tend to
be overhyped. I started hacking on Elastic because
I heard about it on Twitter or in some talk,
and I see this as a mistake because if someone
mentions a program that is cool, it automatically
means that a lot of people are jumping on it,
making it not cool anymore. Of course, it doesn't
apply to huge programs like Google or Facebook,
but if I would be choosing my next program, I
would not go for one that someone recommends me.
And also if you ever ask someone which
program to choose to start bug bounty, I get
asked this a lot, don't do this and don't go for
a program that someone recommends to you. But if
I would hunt on Elastic again, what would I do
differently? First, it's definitely worth it to
invest time to prepare your environment, prepare
your tools, write your own decompiler maybe.
It definitely pays off. I would also spend more
time trying to understand the business side
because from the technical standpoint, of course,
I can understand the functionality and what Kibana is but
I don't even know what is its place in a company.
What do the roles mean in real life? And also how
does Kibana integrate with other products of
Elastic. I think I could have done a better job of
also learning what Logstash is. I know there
is the there is Beats application in scope.
It's a whole infrastructure around
Elasticsearch and I probably should have
invested more time into understanding this and
maybe not choosing the most commonly hacked and
the easiest to setup, which was Kibana.
And also, I think writing my own plugins
is definitely a good way because first, you
start to understand the application from the
developer perspective. But also you can
reach the code which is not reachable
the other way. So you are pretty sure that
there are bugs to be found there. If you want to
try to find a bug that I've missed or maybe you
just want to see how I organize my notes, you can
access my whole Notion page from hunting on Elastic
under this URL: bbre.dev/elastic
And in the next bounty vlog, challenge myself to
jump from different private programs on Hackerone
to test completely different approach. In fact,
I already uploaded one vulnerability that I found
doing this challenge. It was quite a nice SSRF,
which I escalated to account takeover. You can
watch it by clicking the card which is on your
screen right now. And you don't want to miss the
next bounty vlogs, subscribe to the channel!
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye!